Guide to the Wilfrid S. Sellars Papers, 1899-1990 ASP.1991.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research and Writing, 1925-1990; II.
  - Handwritten Notes, 1948-1980; 1.
    - Miscellaneous
      - Mixture of seemingly unrelated items, undated (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
      - Teaching-related materials, undated (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
      - Works in progress, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Pre-Publication Materials, 1941-1983; 2.
    These files contain Sellars's unpublished manuscript drafts, which were the earlier versions of his published works. These manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by manuscript title. In a few instances, the manuscript drafts are augmented by related correspondence. The vast majority of the revisions and inserts added to the manuscripts were done by Sellars. However, there are a few manuscripts that contain editor notations. In general, the revisions range in content from grammatical changes to extensive modifications of Sellars's philosophical arguments. These revisions reveal Sellars's tendency to cross out entire sections of his argument and insert new pages. The bulk of these files are either typed or mimeographed. A small portion of the files are entirely handwritten and can be rather difficult to decipher. The files vary in length. Some of the files provide only one draft of a particular manuscript, while a larger portion of the files actually contain multiple drafts of the manuscript and document various points in the editorial process. Whenever possible, these multiple drafts are arranged chronologically from the earliest to the most developed version. All of the manuscripts are philosophical in nature and focus on Sellars's interests in the areas of epistemology, philosophy of language, philosophy of mind, and ontology.
    - "Abstract Entities", 1962 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - "Actions and Events", 1969 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "Adverbial Theory of the Objects of Sensation", 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3-5)
    - "Are There Non-Deductive Logics", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Aristotelian Philosophies of Mind", 1947 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - "Aristotle and Emergent Evolution", undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - "Aristotle's Metaphysics: An Interpretation", undated (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
    - "Behaviorism, Language, and Meaning", c. 1978 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - "Being and Being Known", undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Belief and the Expression of Belief", 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Berkeley and Descartes", undated (Box 27, Folder 5-7)
    - Carcus Lectures, "Foundations for a Metaphysics of Pure Process", 1978 (Box 27, Folder 8-10)
    - Carcus Lectures, "Foundations for a Metaphysics of Pure Process", 1980-1981 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - "Cincinnati Comments", 1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "Classes as Abstract Entities and the Russell Paradox", 1963 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - "Comments on Maxwell's Meaning Postulates in Scientific Theories", undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - "Comments on McMullin's Matter as Principle", undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - "Concepts as Involving Laws and Inconceivable Without Them", 1948 (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
    - "Conceptual Change", 1972 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - "Conditional Promises and Conditional Intentions", 1980 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "Counterfactuals, Dispositions, and the Causal Modalities", undated (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - "Definition and Analysis", undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Definitions of Naturalism", undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - "Double Knowledge Approach to the Mind Body Problem", 1970 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Empiricism and Abstract Entities", 1954 (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
    - "Empiricism and the Philosophy of Mind", undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - "Epistemology and the New Way of Words", undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - "Essays in Philosophy", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "Fatalism and Determinism", 1964-1968 (Box 30, Folder 2-4)
    - "Form and Content in Ethical Theory", 1967 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - "Givenness and Explanatory Coherence", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
    - "Grammar and Existence: A Preface to Ontology", 1959 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - "Hochberg on Mapping, Meaning, and Metaphysics", 1976 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - "Identity Approach to the Mind-Body Problem", undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "Identity of Linguistic Expressions and the Paradox of Analysis", undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - "Imperatives, Intentions, and the Logic of 'Ought'", 1956-1959 (Box 31, Folder 3-6)
    - "Induction as Vindication", 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
    - "Inference and Meaning", c. 1950 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - "Intentional Realism of Everett Hall", c. 1960 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Intentionality and the Mental", c. 1957 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Intentionality and the Mind-Body Problem", 1952 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Is Critical Realism a Representative Theory of Knowledge?", undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "Is Scientific Realism Tenable?", 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    - "Is There a Synthetic A Priori?", 1952 (Box 32, Folder 9-10)
    - "Kant's Transcendental Idealism", 1974 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "Kant's Transcendental Metaphysics", undated (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
    - "Kant's Views on Sensibility and Understanding", undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - "Language as Thought and as Communication", 1968 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Language of Theories", 1959 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "Language of Theories", 1959 (Oversize 198)
    - "Language, Rules, and Behavior", 1949 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
    - "Leibnitz Rationalism: Scaffolding for a Reconstruction", undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - "The Logic of Probability", 1941 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - "Logical Subjects and Physical Objects", undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - "Meaning as Functional Classification", 1973 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - "Meditations Leibnitziennes", 1965 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Mental Events", 1980 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Metaphysics and the Concept of a Person", 1967 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - "Mind, Meaning, and Behavior", 1952 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Unidentified Manuscripts, 1947-1980 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "More on Givenness and Explanatory Coherence", 1979 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "Naming and Saying", 1961 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "Naturalism and Ontology", 1979-1980 (Box 34, Folder 8-9)
    - "Naturalism and Ontology", 1979-1980 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
    - "Notes on Anselm's Ontological Argument", undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - "A Note on Awareness As", 1978 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - "Notes on Intentionality", 1964 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - "A Note on Popper's Argument for Dualism", c. 1953 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - "A Note on the Form 'Pr(a)'", 1946-1947 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - "On Accepting First Principles", 1965 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - "On the Introduction of Abstract Entities", 1973 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - "On Knowing the Better and Doing the Worse", 1969 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - "On the Logic of Complex Particulars", 1948 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - "On Reasoning About Values", 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 2-5)
    - "Ontology, the A Priori, and Kant", 1967 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "Ontology and the Philosophy of Mind in Russell", 1972 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - "'Ought' and Moral Principles", 1966 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - "Outlines of a Philosophy of Language", 1950 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - "The Paradox of Analysis Resolved", 1963 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - "Particulars", 1950s (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - "Phenomenalism", 1959 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - "Philosophical Perspectives", 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - "Philosophical Perspectives", undated (Oversize 198)
    - "Philosophy and the Scientific Image of Man", 1960 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - "Physical Realism", 1950s (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - "Positivism and Consciousness", undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - "Presupposing", 1954 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - "Provincialism in Philosophy", undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "Pure Pragmatics and Epistemology", 1947 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - "Quotation Marks, Sentences, and Propositions", undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - "Raw Materials, Subjects, and Substrata", c. 1958 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "Realism and the New Way of Words", c. 1946 (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
    - "Reason and the Art of Living in Plato", 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "Reasons, Commands, and Moral Principles", c. 1955 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Reflections on Contrary-to-Duty Imperatives", 1965 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
    - "Reply to Aune", undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "Reply to Donagan", 1971 (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
    - "Reply to Marras", 1972 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Reply to Quine", 1972 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Review of "A History of Western Philosophy", 1934 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Rice on Definitions in Value Theory", 1946 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "The Role of Imagination in Kant's Theory of Experience", 1978 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "Science and Ethics", 1959-1963 (Box 39, Folder 12-13)
    - "Science and Metaphysics: Variations on Kantian Themes", 1976 (Box 40, Folder 1-8)
    - "Science, Perception, and Reality", undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Science, Sense Impressions, a Sensa: A Reply to Cornman", 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Scientific Realism or Irenic Instrumentalism", 1964-1965 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Seeing, Seeming, Sensing", 1971 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "A Semantical Solution of the Mind-Body Problem", 1952 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
    - "Sensa or Sensings: Reflections on the Ontology of Perception", 1976, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 6-7)
    - "Some Problems About Belief", 1967-1968 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Some Reflections on Language Games", 1954 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Some Reflections on Perceptual Consciousness", 1975 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Some Reflections on Thoughts and Things", undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Some Remarks on Kant's Theory of Experience", 1967 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Some Remarks on Kant's Theory of Experience", 1967 (Oversize 198)
    - "The Soul as Craftsman", 1965 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "The Structure of Knowledge", 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
    - "A Study in Leibnitz", undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - "Substance and Form in Aristotle: An Exploration", 1957 (Box 42, Folder 8-9)
    - "Theoretical Explanation", 1963 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "this i or he or it (the thing) which thinks", 1970 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - "Thought and Action", 1964 (Box 43, Folder 1-3)
    - "Time and the World Order", 1957-1959 (Box 43, Folder 5-10)
    - "Towards a Theory of Predication", 1982-1983 (Box 44, Folder 1-3)
    - "Towards a Theory of the Categories", 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Truth and Correspondence", 1961 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Vlastos and 'The Third Man", 1954 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Vlastos and 'The Third Man': A Rejoinder", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
    - "Volitions Re-Affirmed", 1975 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts of Other Authors, 1925-1990; 3.
    These materials represent unpublished versions of articles, book chapters, and conference papers, with the vast majority being articles intended for publication in scholarly journals. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by author and in the case of coauthors, the manuscript is filed by the primary listed author. While this series contains works written by Sellars's peers, the authors here are largely his former students. These student manuscripts reveal their development as professionals in the philosophical community. Most of the manuscripts do not contain annotations, and those that do have minimal markings consisting of underlined sections and minimal commentary in the margins. Approximately half of the manuscripts contain cover letters, which generally introduce the manuscript and solicit comments from Sellars. The topics covered in these manuscripts are strictly philosophical and center on Sellars's expertise in philosophy of mind, epistemology, meaning, pragmatism, and history of philosophy. Some notable exceptions to the minimal annotations are the manuscripts originating from Rigoberto Juarez-Paz, which were heavily annotated. Also noteworthy are the manuscripts of Robert Turnball's "Aseity and Dependence in Leibniz's Metaphysics" and Gregory Vlastos's "The Senonian Argument Against Plurality," which contain detailed critiques from Sellars. While a generalization, one could also state that the manuscripts Sellars most heavily analyzed were those that referred to his own works.
    - Abraham, William, "Compossibility", 1971 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Adams, E. M., "The Scientific and the Humanistic Times of Man-In-The-World", 1969 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Marilyn, "Ockham on Predication and Ontology", c. 1977 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Robert M., "Leibniz Phenomenalism", 1980 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Adler, Mortimer, "Sense-Cognition", undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Ager, T., Untitled, c. 1966 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Albritton, Rogers, "Forms of Particular Substances in Aristotle's Metaphysics", c. 1957 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Alexander, H. G., "Necessary Truth", c. 1954 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Allaire, Edwin, Review of Science and Metaphysics, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Allen, Reginald E.
      - "The Interpretation of Plato's Parmenides", 1964 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - "Participation and Predication in Plato's Middle Dialogues", undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Allis, James, "Turning to the Good: A Study of Plato's, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Alpern, Ken
      - "The Acceptability and Intelligibility of Action at a Distance Descartes-Boscovich", 1974 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Foundation of a logical-linguistic framework, undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Alston, William
      - "The Elucidation of Religious Statements", undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - "Immediate Knowledge", c. 1981 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - "Linguistic Arts", c. 1962 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - "Meaning and Use", 1963 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - "Particulars and Bare", c. 1952 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - "The Problem of Meaning in Theology", undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - "Wants, Beliefs, and Actions", c. 1961 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Amaral, Pedro
      - The adverbial analysis of events, c. 1973 (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - "Aristotle De Interpretatione", 1976 (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - "Descartes Against the Species", 1975 (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - "The History of Given Harmony", 1980s (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - "Kant's Concept of a Thing", c. 1974 (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - Kant's definition of judgment, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 27)
      - "Kant's Logic of the Categorical Judgment", c. 1973 (Box 45, Folder 28)
      - Material roles of inference, c. 1973 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - "Natural Coordination, Harmony, Sympathy, and Synthetic", undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - "A Note on Sellars "Picturing", 1983 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - "Objective Reality: First and Second Intentions", undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - "The Soul as the Form of the Body", undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - "Truth and Predication in Descartes", undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Anapolitanos, D.A., "Leibniz and the Relation of "Spatially Between'", 1983 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Alan Ross
      - "A Completeness Theorem for the System E of Entailment", c. 1956 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - "Entailment and Negation", c. 1958 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - "The Formal Analysis of Normative Systems", 1956 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - "Independent Axiom Schemata for the Pure Theory of Entailment", c. 1959 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - "On Professor Martin's Beliefs", undated (Oversize 198)
      - "A Pure Calculus of Entailment", 1960 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Anderson, John M., "Why Categories?", 1978 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Anderson, Myron, "The Paradox of Analysis and Synonymity of Belief", 1955 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Anderson, Wallace, "Cartesian Motion", undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Anscombe, G. M. E. et al., "The Listener", 1957 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Aquist, Lennart, "Improved Formulations of Act-Utilitarianism", c. 1968 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Armstrong, D .M.
      - "Laws of Nature as Relations Between Universals, and as Universals", 1981 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - "Letter about Prague", undated (Box 46, Folder 19)
      - "Self-Profile", 1983 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - "A Theory of Perception", undated (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Ashby, W. Ross, "Induction, Prediction, and Decision-Making in Cybernetic Systems", 1961 (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - Aune, Bruce
      - "Abilities, Modalities, and Free Will", c. 1960 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - "Animadversions on the Philosophical Problem of 'Other' Minds", c. 1960 (Box 46, Folder 24)
      - "The Behaviorist's Assumptions Reconsidered", undated (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - Chapter 6: Conclusion, c. 1955 (Box 46, Folder 26)
      - "Chisholm on Self-Identity", 1972 (Box 46, Folder 27)
      - "Comments on Cornman", c. 1962 (Box 46, Folder 28)
      - "Comments on Sellars' 'Phenomenalism'", c. 1963 (Box 46, Folder 29)
      - "Fatalism and Professor Taylor", 1962 (Box 46, Folder 30)
      - "Feelings, Moods, and Introspection", c. 1960 (Box 46, Folder 31)
      - "Feigl on the Mind-Body Problem", c. 1961 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - "Formal Logic and Practical Reasoning", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - "Grossman on Intentionality", 1965 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - "If", c. 1963 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - "Intention", undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - "Is There an Analytic A Priori?", c. 1963 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Kant's Theory of Morals, c. 1977 (Box 47, Folder 7-9)
      - "Kenny on Practical Inference", 1973 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - "Knowing and Merely Thinking", c. 1958 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - "Necessity, Statements, and Rules", c. 1964 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - "On Postulating Universals", c. 1971 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - "On Thoughts and Feeling", c. 1960 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - "Other Minds", 1960 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - "The Paradox of Empiricism", undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - "Possibility", undated (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - "Prichard, Action, and Volition", c. 1972 (Box 47, Folder 18)
      - "The Problem of Other Minds", undated (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - "Quine on Translation and Reference", 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Review of Materialism and Sensations, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 21)
      - Science and Metaphysics: Variations on Kantian Themes, c. 1968 (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - "Self-Knowledge and Two Types of Psychological Concepts", 1960 (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - "Sellars on Practical Inference", c. 1977 (Box 47, Folder 24)
      - "Sellars on Practical Reasoning: A Critique", 1970 (Box 47, Folder 25)
      - "Some Notes on Style", undated (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - "Some Remarks on and Argument by Chisholm", c. 1969 (Box 47, Folder 27)
      - "Thinking", c. 1966 (Box 47, Folder 28)
      - ""True" and "Truly": A Reply to White", undated (Box 47, Folder 29)
      - Untitled, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1-4)
    - Austin, J. L., "Truth", undated (Oversize 198)
    - Bach, Emmon
      - "A Framework for Syntax and Semantics", c. 1976 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - "Nouns and Nounphrases", c. 1967 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - "On Raising and More on Raising", 1976-1977 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - "Topics in English Metaphysics", c. 1977 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Bacon, John
      - "The Generic Conception of the Universal", 1971 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - "The Pragmatics of Knowing and Seeing", c. 1974 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - "The Semantics of Generic The", c. 1972 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - "The Universal Abstracted", 1969 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Baier, Annette
      - Descartes seminar papers, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - "Helping Hume to 'Complete the Union'", c. 1977 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - "Hume on Heaps and Bundles", c. 1977 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - "The Idea of the True God in Descartes", undated (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - "Intention, Practical Knowledge, and Representation", 1975 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - "The Intentionality of Intentions", c. 1976 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - "Mixing Memory and Desire", 1974 (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - "Second Person, Past", 1978 (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - "Spinoza's Truth", 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Baier, Kurt
      - "Preference and the Good of Man", 1974 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - "Value and Fact", undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - "Welfare and Preference", c. 1965 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Baker, Lynne, "The Ontological Status of Temporal Becoming", 1975 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Bartley, W.W.
      - "Karl Barth: An Appreciation", c. 1963 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - "Theory of Language and Philosophy of Science as Instruments of Educational Reform: Wittgenstein and Popper as Austrian Schoolteachers", 1968 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Bastak, Shafikah, "The Analysis of 'By' in Action Sequence", 1975 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Baylie, Charles, "Comments on the Symposium on Logical Subjects and Physical Objects", undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Beck, Lewis White, "'Was-Must Be' and 'Is-Ought' in Hume", undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Beer, Michelle
      - "Is Temporal Becoming Mind-Dependent?", 1987 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - "Temporal Indexicals and the Passage of Time", 1987 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Belnap, Nuel
      - "Questions: Their Presuppositions, and How They Can Fail to Arise", 1967 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - "Seeing to It That: A Canonical Form for Agentives", 1988 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - "Tautological Entailments", 1959 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Benacerraf, Paul, "The Last Logicist", undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Bennett, Jonathan, "The Simplicity of the Soul", 1967 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Bergmann, Gustav
      - "Acts", c. 1960 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - "The Logic of Probability", c. 1941 (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - "On Non-Perceptual Intuition", 1949 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - "The Philosophical Significance of Modal Logic", 1957 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - "Probability as a Problem of the Philosophy of Science", undated (Oversize 198)
      - ",Professor Ayer's Analysis of Knowing"c. 1947 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - "Reduction", undated (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - "Remarks concerning Professor Quine's 'Notes on Existence and Identity'", c. 1943 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - Review of Gestalt Psychology, c. 1947 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      - "Two Criteria for an Ideal Language", undated (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Berlyne, Daniel, "The Motivation of Inductive Behavior", c. 1961 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Bernstein, Richard J., "The Limits of Justification", c. 1958 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Binkley, Robert
      - "Austin's Performatives", 1959 (Box 49, Folder 25)
      - "Change of Belief or Change of Meaning?", 1972 (Box 49, Folder 26)
      - "The Ultimate Justification of Moral Rules", 1971 (Box 49, Folder 27)
      - "The Ultimate Justification of Morality", 1959 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Blackburn, Thomas, "Truth and Generality: On Peirce's Relation to 'Methodological Pragmatism'", 1974 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Blake, Ralph Mason, "Why Not Hedonism? A Protest", 1926 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Boer, Steven E. and Lycan, William G., "The Myth of Semantic Presupposition", 1976 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Bogen, James, "A Paper", undated (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Bohm, David
      - "Some Remarks on the Notion of the Order for the Bellagoio Conference on Theoretical Biology", 1967 (Box 49, Folder 33)
      - "Space, Time, and Quantum Theory Understood in Terms of Discrete Structural Process", 1965 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Bonevac, David
      - "Countability and Quantification", 1981 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - "Kant on Existence and Analyticity", c. 1975 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - "Reduction and Mathematical Truth", c. 1978 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Bonzon, Roman
      - "On Supervenience and Ethical Theory", 1985 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - "Respecting Realism", 1988 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Bradie, Michael